EECS 4413 Group Project   
 
Deliverable 3 
  
Purpose of the  Deliverable  
The purpose of this deliverable is to produce :   
a) The back -end implementation of the use cases , following REST principles  and modern 
runtime deployment requirements.  
b) The front -end and UI of the project  
c) A distinguishable feature for your project  
d) Test cases, delivered as a curl /postman  script file  
 
In this Assignment, you will learn to  program the full stack of an e -commerce application  and to 
deploy and operate it as containers  
Due  
Please check e -class regularly for any updates regarding the submission process  and deadlines . 
One submission per group.  
Late Penalty  
Late project will be accepted for up to two days after the due date. Submissions late up to 24 hours 
will incur a penalty of 20%. No submissions after 48th hour of the deadline are accepted. The same 
time windows hold if there is an extension given by the instructor.  
Group Effort  
This stage of the project is expected to be a group effort, with each member of the group contributing 
equally . The contribution of each member should be documented. Also, each member should 
understand the entire project, even of their focus was on specific parts. In the face-to-face demo with 
the instructor or /and TA, students should be able to explain any parts of the code  in their project .  If it 
is determined that you are guilty of cheating on the assignment, you could receive a grade of zero 
with a not ice of this offence submitted to the Dean of your home faculty for inclusion in your 
academic record.  
What to Hand in  
Your submission, as noted above, will be electronically in the form of an archive (e.g. zip) file. Please 
check e -class regularly for any changes related to the submission process. You are to complete the 
deliverable by providing.   
-the server and client -side implementations as a zip file  (Maven project) ; 
-a readme file with installation instructions; if you host your application at an external site, please 
provide the url  as well as any credentials needed to operate it  
-A script file with curl or postman test cases  for the backend ; the testcases should test for robustness 
(user wrong inputs) , scalability and security . 
-an updated design document that explains the distinguishable feature,  changes in the design, 
testcases, project plan and team meeting logs  as well as the performance and security/testing 
report . Append t he new content to Deliverable 2 document.  
Note: you are asked to provide a distinguishable feature for your project. This is in addition to original 
project specifications. The use case can be  
ò A Gen AI use case  (see the lecture and tutorial on AI and MPC)  
ò . For example , you might want to create a chat bot that, either  
o Allow users to use natural language to interact with your application  
o Allow a  business  admin to chat with the system abou t the business aspects of the e -
auction site (bid statistics)  
o Allow the DevOps team to monitor the application (logs and metrics), assists in 
mitigation strategies  
ò A feature that improves the quality of your application. For example, you can have logging , 
instrumentation for observability  and you can make your application self -adaptive for 
performance or availability  using AI or non -Ai techniques . 
ò Any other feature that you might choose. Discuss it with the instructor and TAs  
Development and Runtime Frameworks  
 
For Deliveries 3, you are allowed to use any technology presented in class and encouraged to go beyond 
the APIs covered in Labs and lectures.  You can also use other technologies, not presented in the class.  
For example, you can use React ( https://react.dev/learn).  However , it is expected that each member of 
the team can contribute to and understand each part of the project and therefore agrees on the 
technologies used in the project. If you use other technologies, you should discuss it with the TA or the 
professor.  
 
Team Development and Deployment  
 
Ideally, the application has multiple microservices  accessed through a web gateway.  
ò To be considered microservices based, the application should , at minimum , have the middle -tier 
microservice based, with REST APIs , testable with curl/postman scripts . 
ò It is required  that you show your final microservice architecture in the design document.  
 
Ideally, the application is packaged in Docker containers, can be pulled from Docker repository,  and run.  
ò To be considered cloud enabled, at minimum, the backend is packaged into a container that can 
be pulled and run using docker commands.  
ò It is highly recommended that you show your deployment diagram in the design document  
 
The front end, UI, must  be functional and allows easy navigation between different roles and use cases. 
Although the style , look and feel, are very important in modern e -commerce applications, they are not the 
focus  of this course.  
 
If you use  GitHub , provide the link to it and give your TA access to it. Otherwise, provide your source files 
as a zip file. The TA should see your code and scripts.  
 
In Person Demo  
 
For in person demo, you will mee t the TA or professor. Be ready to show:  
    -how you deploy and run your application  
    -highlights the use cases for the application  
    -explain the design document and its sections  
    -answer any questions about the code, architecture, deployment  
 
 
 
 
 
