Group                                                            ________ ____________________ __________________________  
No. of Members                                            _______ ________ _____________ __________________________  
 
EECS 4 413 - Project  Report  Mark  
Implementation   /75 
The degree in which a ll use cases are implemented  in UI   and working   
Distinguished use case  or feature (not specified by instructor, each team can choose)   
UI navigability and support of use cases   
Robustness  (including client side validations)   
The degree in which it uses cloud and containers   
The degree in which if follows REST  (HATEOS)  and microservice principles   
Ease of install/run   
     
Additional Comments:  
 
 
 
Report Content  /10 
Explanation of a distinguishable feature ( examples: LLM based chatbot  to support bidding using 
NL, autoscaling with agents ). A short report about validation. For example, show the accuracy of 
the chatbot or autoscalers and examples of system prompt you tried to achieve high accuracy.   
Performance Report  (Response time as a function of arrival rate, use JMeter to generate load)   
Testing report  (describe the failure rates, estimate the cpu testing time needed to eliminate all 
bugs. Assume v_0=500. )   
Team member part  (description of the work of each team member)   
Report Writing Quality          /5 
Consistency (box names, legends, etc)   
Diagrams and tables are explained in the text (Diagrams have legends)   
References inserted where necessary   
Document is proofread   
Use of fonts is consistent across the document   
Screenshots of UML diagrams with readable fonts, edges and arrows   
Demo quality      /10 
Additional Comments:  
 
 
  
 
 
 
 
 
Penalty  for being late, failing to acknowledge GenAI use , 
not understanding the code   
Total  /100 
  
 
